[{"id":"1618","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:l","question":"Who was Nephi’s nephew that wrote the third book in the Book of Mormon?","answer":"Enos","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1619","type":"multi","ref":"Enos1:1","question":"It came to pass that Enos knew that his father was a_____ man.","answer":"Just","options":["Just","Holy","Unworthy"]},{"id":"1620","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:1","question":"Was a prophet of the Lord and also the father of Enos?","answer":"Jacob","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1621","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:1,27","question":"How many chapters are in the book of Enos?","answer":["One","1"],"options":["fill"]},{"id":"1622","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:1","question":"Enos was not taught in the language of his father, therefore he made up his own.","answer":"false","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1623","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:1","question":"Who taught Enos of the nurture and admonition of the Lord?","answer":"Father","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1624","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:2","question":"And I will tell you of the_____ which I had before God, before I received a remission of my sins.","answer":"Wrestle","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1625","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:2","question":"The word wrestle is only mentioned once in the Book of Mormon.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1626","type":"multi","ref":"Enos1:3","question":"Enos went to hunt_____ in the forest.","answer":"Beasts","options":["Wild Game","Bears","Beasts"]},{"id":"1627","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:3","question":"Enos’s father spoke to him concerning eternal_____, and the joy of the saints, and those words sank deep into his heart.","answer":"Life","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1628","type":"multi","ref":"Enos1:4","question":"And my soul hungered; and I kneeled down before my_____.","answer":"Maker","options":["Alter","Maker","Pile Of Gold"]},{"id":"1629","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:4","question":"Enos cried unto his Maker in mighty prayer and supplication for his own soul.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1630","type":"multi","ref":"Enos1:4","question":"Enos cried unto his Maker all day long, and when the night came, he raised his voice high that it reached the_____.","answer":"Heavens","options":["Heavens","Moon","Stars"]},{"id":"1631","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:5","question":"Who said: “Enos, thy sins are forgiven thee, and thou shalt be blessed”","answer":"God","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1632","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:6","question":"And I, _____, knew that God could not lie; wherefore, my guilt was swept away.","answer":"Enos","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1633","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:7","question":"Enos asked the Lord how it was done that his sins were forgiven.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1634","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:8","question":"How was Enos’ guilt for his sins forgiven?","answer":"faith","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1635","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:8","question":"The Lord told Enos that two years would pass away before Christ would manifest himself in the flesh.","answer":"false","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1636","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:8","question":"The Lord told Enos that his faith alone did not make him whole.","answer":"false","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1637","type":"multi","ref":"Enos1:9","question":"When Enos heard the words of the Lord he began to feel a desire, for the welfare of his brethren, the_____.","answer":"Nephites","options":["Lamanites","Nephites","Zoramites"]},{"id":"1638","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:9","question":"Enos poured out his whole soul unto God, for the welfare of the Nephites.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1639","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:10","question":"Enos struggled in the spirit while he was praying for the welfare of the Nephites.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1640","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:10","question":"The Lord told Enos that he would visit his brethren according to their_____ in keeping his commandment.","answer":"Diligence","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1641","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:10","question":"Enos was told by the Holy Ghost that the land of promise was a holy land.","answer":"false","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1642","type":"multi","ref":"Enos1:10","question":"The Lord told Enos that he would curse the land of promise save it be for the cause of_____.","answer":"Iniquity","options":["Iniquity","Wars","Contentions"]},{"id":"1643","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:10","question":"Their transgressions will I bring down with sorrow upon their own_____.","answer":"Heads","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1644","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:11","question":"After Enos heard the words of the Lord, his faith began to be unshaken in the Lord.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1645","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:11","question":"Enos prayed unto the Lord with many long struggles, for his brethren, the_____.","answer":"Lamanites","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1646","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:12","question":"Enos prayed and labored with all his diligence unto the Lord.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1647","type":"multi","ref":"Enos1:12","question":"The Lord said unto Enos that he would grant his desires because of his_____.","answer":"Faith","options":["Wishes","Faith","Humble Heart"]},{"id":"1648","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:13","question":"Enos desired of the Lord: That if the Nephites should fall because of transgression and the Lamanites should not be destroyed, that he would preserve the record of his people.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1649","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:13","question":"Enos desired that the record of his people be brought forth at some future day unto the_____; that they may be brought forth unto salvation.","answer":"Lamanites-","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1650","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:14","question":"For at the present our struggles were vain in restoring Lamanites to the true_____.","answer":"Faith","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1651","type":"multi","ref":"Enos1:14","question":"The Lamanites swore in their wrath that if it were possible, they would destroy the Nephites and their records, and also all the_____ of their fathers.","answer":"Customs","options":["Traditions","Customs","Their Sign Language."]},{"id":"1652","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:15","question":"Enos cried unto the Lord continually because he knew that he would preserve their records.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1653","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:15","question":"The Lord said to Enos:  “Whatsoever thing ye shall ask in_____, believing that ye shall receive in the name of Christ, ye shall receive it”.","answer":"Faith","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1654","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:15","question":"Because Enos had faith in the Lord; he knew that whatsoever he asked of him, he would receive it.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1655","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:16","question":"The Lord_____ with Enos that he would bring forth his records unto the Lamanites in his own due time.","answer":"Covenanted","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1656","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:16","question":"Enos said that the Lord would bring forth his records unto the Lamanites when he would still be alive.","answer":"false","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1657","type":"multi","ref":"Enos1:17","question":"Enos knew that the Lord would do with the records that which he had covenanted with him; wherefore his soul did_____.","answer":"Rest","options":["Rest","Yearn","Wander"]},{"id":"1658","type":"multi","ref":"Enos1:18","question":"The Lord compared Enos’ faith like that of his_____.","answer":"Fathers","options":["Brothers","Fathers","Children"]},{"id":"1659","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:19","question":"Enos went about among the people of Nephi, _____ of things to come.","answer":"Prophesying","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1660","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:19","question":"Enos testified to the Nephites of the things which he had heard and seen.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1661","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:20","question":"And I Enos, _____ record that the people of Nephi did seek diligently to restore the Lamanites unto the true faith of God.","answer":"Bear","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1662","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:20","question":"Enos and his brothers’ labors were in vain because the Lamanites hatred was fixed, and they were led by their evil nature.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1663","type":"multi","ref":"Enos1:20","question":"Because of their evil nature, the Lamanites became a wild, ferocious, and____ people.","answer":"Bloodthirsty","options":["Mean","Dirty","Bloodthirsty"]},{"id":"1664","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:20","question":"According to Enos, the Lamanites were full of idolatry and filth1ness; feeding upon beast’s of_____, and dwelling in tents.","answer":"Prey","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1665","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:20","question":"The Lamanites would wander in the wilderness with a short skin girdle about their loins and their_____ shaven.","answer":"Heads","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1666","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:20","question":"The Lamanites skill was not in the bow, and in the cimeter, and the ax.","answer":"false","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1667","type":"multi","ref":"Enos1:20","question":"Many of the Lamanites did eat nothing but_____ meat; continually seeking to destroy the Nephites.","answer":"Raw","options":["Raw","Unhealthy","Good"]},{"id":"1668","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:21","question":"In his book Enos, he describes the way of life in the Nephite culture and also of the Lamanites.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1669","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:21","question":"The people of Nephi did not till the ground but raised cattle instead.","answer":"false","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1670","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:21","question":"The Nephites did till the land, and raised all kinds of grain, and fruit, and flocks of herds.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1671","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:21","question":"The Nephites raised_____ of all manner of cattle of every kind, and goats, and wild goats.","answer":"Flocks","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1672","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:21","question":"During the time that Enos was on the earth the Nephites did not have horses.","answer":"false","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1673","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:22","question":"Enos said that there were many prophets in the land among them but that the people were a_____ people, hard to understand.","answer":"Stiffnecked","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1674","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:23","question":"Enos said that there was exceeding harshness, preaching and prophesying of_____, and contentions and destructions.","answer":"Wars","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1675","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:23","question":"Because of the exceeding harshness, preaching and prophesying of wars, the people were continually reminded of death.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1676","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:23","question":"The people were continually reminded of the judgments and _____ of God.","answer":"Power","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1677","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:23","question":"Because of the exceeding great plainness of speech, it would keep the people from going down speedily to destruction.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1678","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:24","question":"Enos did not see many wars between the Nephites and Lamanites in the course of his days.","answer":"false","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1679","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:25","question":"Enos was wrought upon the power of God that he must preach and prophesy unto the people and declare the word according to the truth which is in_____.","answer":"Christ","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1680","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:26","question":"Enos declared in all his days to the truth which is in Christ, and rejoiced in it above that of the world.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1681","type":"bool","ref":"Enos1:27","question":"Enos said that he knew that he would go to the place of his rest, which is with his Redeemer; and knew that in him he would rest.","answer":"true","options":["true","false"]},{"id":"1682","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:27","question":"Enos rejoiced in the day that his mortal shall put on_____; and shall stand before him; and would see his face with pleasure.","answer":"Immortality","options":["fill"]},{"id":"1683","type":"fill","ref":"Enos1:27","question":"Enos said that the Lord would say to him:  “Come unto me, ye blessed, there is a place prepared for you in the_____, of my Father”.","answer":"Mansions","options":["fill"]}]